<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section version="5.0"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:mth="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xml:id="create_user">
    <title>Create a user</title>
    <screenshot>
        <title>Select Users menu item</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                    fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/select_user_menu.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
    <para>User accounts already registered will appear as a list as seen below.</para>
    <screenshot>
        <title>Search by user name</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                    fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/search_user_by_name.png" format="PNG"
                />
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Open the <emphasis role="bold">Users</emphasis> app and click <emphasis
                    role="bold">User</emphasis>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Add new</emphasis>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Select whether you want to fill in all the personal user information , or invite
                the user by email to complete the rest of the user information:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Create account with user details</emphasis>: Choose
                        this if you would like to enter all the details of the new user such as
                        name, password, etc.</para>
                    <para>If you choose this action, then enter the following information: user
                        name, password, surname, first name, E-mail, OpenID account (if any) and
                        mobile phone number (if any).</para>
                    <para>After you finish adding the user, the account will be ready for them to
                        use with the user name and password that you supply.</para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <title>Select Users menu item</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                                    fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/user_management_details.png"
                                    format="PNG"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Email invitation to create account</emphasis>:
                        Choose this if you would like to send by email an invitation for the user to
                        return to the system and finish setting up their user account. The user will
                        then return to the system and fill in most of their personal information.
                        The account that the user finishes setting up will be limited according to
                        how you configure it below.</para>
                    <para>Note that you may not select this option to create an account with
                        &quot;critical&quot; system authorities such as All, Scheduling
                        Administration, Perform maintenance tasks, Merge organisation units,
                        Eliminate duplicate data elements, SQL View Management, Change system
                        settings, and List, Add or Delete user roles.</para>
                    <para>If you choose this action, then enter the email address to which the
                        invitation should be sent. If you want to, you may also enter the user name
                        that the account will have. If you leave the user name empty, then the user
                        may choose their own user name when they respond to the invitation (as long
                        as it is not taken already for another user.)</para>
                    <para>After you finish adding the new user, two emails will be sent to the
                        address you provided. One contains a unique web link by which the user can
                        return to the system and activate their account by entering the rest of
                        their user information. The other email contains a unique code that they
                        must enter into the system in order to complete the registration, after
                        following the link in the first email. The user must finish setting up the
                        account within three months, or the invitation becomes invalid.</para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <title>Select Users menu item</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                                    fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/user_management_invite.png"
                                    format="PNG"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Select an <emphasis role="bold">Interface language</emphasis>.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T160329+0100" comment="Reword."?>
            <para>You can select a language into which fixed elements of the DHIS2 user interface
                have been translated.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Select a <emphasis role="bold">Database language</emphasis>.</para>
            <para>You can select a language into which implementation-supplied items have been
                translated in the database, for example data element names or organisation unit
                level names.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T160625+0100" comment="Verify step with SME."?>
            <para>In the <emphasis role="bold">Available roles</emphasis> section, double-click the
                user roles you want to assign to the user.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Select <emphasis role="bold">Data capture and maintenance organisation
                    units</emphasis>.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T161240+0100" comment="Rewrite"?>
            <para>Users must be assigned to at least one data capture and maintenance organisation
                unit. Users will have access to all children of the organisation units which have
                been assigned to them. For instance, if a user has been assigned to a district which
                has several facilities contained in the district, the user would have access to the
                district&apos;s data, as well as all of the facilities contained within the
                district. The data approval organisation units control for which organisation units
                the user can do data entry.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T161446+0100" comment="Review step."?>
            <para>Select <emphasis role="bold">Data output and
                    <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T160942+0100" comment="Why analysis here and analytics further down?"?>analysis<?oxy_comment_end?>
                    organisation units</emphasis>.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
            <para>You can assign a users to any number of data view organisation units. This
                controls which organisation units the user can view aggregated data for in analysis
                <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T161314+0100" comment="Which apps?"?>modules<?oxy_comment_end?>.</para>
            <important>
                <para> Giving access to an organisation unit implicitly gives access to all
                    organisation units below it in the organisation unit hierarchy. Thus, you should
                    not select the descendants of an organisation unit which you have already
                    selected. As an example, if the user has been assigned to a district, you should
                    not (and not need to) select the facilities within that district.</para>
                <para>Note that data view organisation units are optional. If you do not specify
                    any, the user will have access to the full organisation unit hierarchy for
                    viewing aggregated data. As with the data capture organisation units,
                        <emphasis>you should not select descendant organisation units of a unit
                        which you have already selected</emphasis>. </para>
            </important>
            <para>In several places in the analysis
                <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T161421+0100" comment="Which apps?"?>modules<?oxy_comment_end?>
                one can select &quot;user organisation unit&quot; for the organisation unit
                dimension. This mechanism will first attempt to use the data view organisation units
                linked to the current user. If not found, it will use the data capture organisation
                units. If the user has been assigned to multiple organisation units, the use of
                &quot;user organisation unit&quot; may result in unpredictable behavior.</para>
            <screenshot>
                <title>User management screen</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                            fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/user_management_fewer_options.png"
                            format="PNG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Show more options</emphasis>.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T160625+0100" comment="Verify step with SME."?>
            <para>(Optional) In the <emphasis role="bold">Available user groups</emphasis> section,
                double-click the user groups you want to assign to the user.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T160625+0100" comment="More information needed. What do you do in this step?"?>
            <para>(Optional) In the <emphasis role="bold">Available dimension restrictions for data
                    analytics</emphasis> section, double-click the ?? groups you want to assign to
                the user.</para>
            <?oxy_comment_end?>
            <para>You can restrict the values this user sees in data
                <?oxy_comment_start author="cecilia" timestamp="20161111T161728+0100" comment="In which apps?"?>analytics<?oxy_comment_end?>
                by selecting dimensions that will restrict the users view. For example, let&apos;s
                say you have defined <emphasis role="italic">Implementing Partner</emphasis> as a
                category option group set, and you have shared with this user only one or more
                specific implementing partners (category option groups.) If you want to insure that
                the user does not see totals in analytics that include values from other groups,
                assign <emphasis role="italic">Implementing Partner</emphasis> to this user. This
                insures that any data visible to the user through DHIS2 analytics will be filtered
                to select only the Implementing Partner category option group(s) which are visible
                to the user.</para>
            <screenshot>
                <title>User management screen</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                            fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/user_management_more_options.png"
                            format="PNG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</section>