<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section version="5.0"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:mth="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xml:id="mgt_userrole">
    <title>Manage user roles</title>
    <para>As part of creating a user name you are required to define the user role. Do so by
        clicking on <emphasis role="italic">User Role</emphasis> on the left side of the displayed
        screen. This will lead you to the User role management page where you can click on
            <guibutton>Add new</guibutton> to create a new role.</para>
    <screenshot>
        <title>Add new user role</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                    fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/add_user_role.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
    <para>The following screen will open and here in the first text box you need to give a <emphasis
            role="italic">Name</emphasis> of the Role such as Super User, Admin User, etc. The
        second text box called <emphasis role="italic">Description</emphasis> gives more information
        about the type of User Role that is being created for e.g. State Admin User, District Data
        Entry.</para>
    <screenshot>
        <title>Role maintenance page</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata width="80%" align="center"
                    fileref="resources/images/dhis2UserManual/role_maintenance_page.png"
                    format="PNG" wordsize=""/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
    <para>Next you will specify the particular data set(s) that are to be made available to the
        particular role. You will also need to specify the type of <emphasis role="italic"
            >Authority</emphasis> to be given to the particular user. For each of the three options
        namely Datasets, Reports and Authorities user can select multiple options from the scroll
        down menu provided against each field. A user can choose multiple options either by moving
        them one-by-one.</para>
    <para>In order for particular users to be able to enter data, you must add them to both a
        dataset as well as an organisational unit level. You can also select multiple datasets
        individually by pressing the Ctrl key on the keyboard and clicking on individual
        datasets.</para>
    <para>Finally when you have entered the required fields click on <guibutton>Save</guibutton>
        which is located on the lower part of the displayed screen. The desired user role and
        related authorisation will be saved to the database, and can then be assigned to a
        particular user.</para>
</section>
